In this video, we are going to discuss
car insurance renewal tips.
Yes, so see, if your
car insurance has expired,
what things should you keep in mind before renewing it?
How is the online review done? Should you get it done
through an agent,
online, or from a showroom? How do
you select the best car insurance company?
On-Damages, Third Party
Insurance, Stand-Alone, Health Insurance,
Comprehensive? What is the difference between them? What
should be the ideal IDV value?
What is RO DAB? What is NCB?
Which add-on should you get and which should you not
get? How can you reduce your premium? I am going to
explain all this in this one
video, so please
watch the entire video. I have already provided you with all the comparison links and
support links
in the description box.
First, understand the types of car insurance
because many people do
n't understand this here. So, whenever
you are buying a brand new car,
you always get a one-year plus three segment,
which means you have one-year on-damages coverage.
And you have your third insurance for a year,
which is compulsory as per the regulations here,
so if you
take out your receipt of your
insurance etc. and see, then you will find
two sections in it, one for own
damages for which the premium will be paid separately
and one for third party
premium, so see, what does own damages mean,
if your vehicle meets with an
accident, gets stolen or gets caught
in any disaster due to natural calamity,
then whatever
loss is there in your vehicle, the
insurance company provides you that money, gets your
vehicle repaired
etc. as per its IDV
value, plus what happens in third party insurance,
if you have hit someone else in front with your vehicle, then all the
legal and financial coverage of the person in front is
covered under third party insurance, so
taking third party insurance
is compulsory in India, without this you
cannot drive on the road, whereas when you
take the vehicle, here you have
Comprehensive insurance is available, that is,
both own damages and third party are basically covered here. Now let's
talk about
how to renew your car insurance. Then
I will tell you later and will provide you some tips
which you have to keep in mind. So the
first thing you have to do is from
where your insurance is already running
because as soon as you
take the car out of the showroom, by default the showroom people
insure you.
Yes, so look here, first of all,
whichever insurance company you have here,
like IC,
ADFC, TA, AAG, any other
company, then first of all you should
go to the company's website,
through the broker, or go to the showroom and get your
renewal quote. It is
not that you
cannot check it online here. For an example,
suppose if you have a Maruti's car, then simply
Maruti's has a separate
insurance blocking platform.
Enter your policy number or your registration number here.  It will fetch you the complete details and tell you
how much the renewal will cost. Similarly,
suppose you have an IIC Lord
policy, then you can directly
go to the website and enter your policy number and you
can also check the quotation etc. directly on the ICC Lord website. Now see guys,
what is there in the quotation here, the third
party premium will always remain
fixed for you. Yes, that means no matter
from which company you take third party insurance,
it will always remain as a fixed amount
because IRDA decides the
rates on the sale. So here, if you
look at the third party insurance of any company, you will always see the same rates. So,
after taking out the quotation etc., there are two-three other companies'
sites, you should go there and
check the premium, like the Policy Bazaar
website. You simply enter your vehicle
number etc. and according to your
IDV value,
it will give you many quotations here.
Now, there are many
elements inside it.  There is zero down payment, 24
ba roadside
assistance, which add should not be done,
I will tell you later, now simply you just
understand the process, there is another
leading insurance company in India called A,
here also simply, like if you enter your vehicle
number etc., then simply brother,
according to your ID value, it will
tell you the premium etc., so in this way
you can compare the premium etc.
and along with this, IIDA
releases a report here every year, I will
also give you this report in the description box
where the income claim settlement ratio is calculated, that is,
how much premium a company is
earning in a year and out of that, how much is the
age premium here, that is,
how much is the customer's claim being settled here, so
here you will get
to see the percentage wise claim of each company
and along with this there is also a claim
settlement ratio which you will
also get to see on the Policy Bazaar website
and like if A also  If you
look, you'll see something like 99 percent,
so you can compare based on that.
Now,
before renewing your insurance, there are a few points
you need to keep in mind. The first, most
important point is the ID value of
the car, and your premium is
decided based on this. What is IDV value?
Depreciation keeps accruing on your car.
Now, if you don't want to check this,
I'll give you a link
in the description box.
Simply enter your vehicle type, state,
year, month, and make. The
variant of your car.
You'll get the IDV value of your car
here.
And if your car is more than 5 years old, then
your
definition of 50 percent starts applying. Now, the
special thing about IDV value is that
you can increase
or decrease this IDV value if you enter this
value here.  If you increase, your
premium will also increase here. If
you decrease, your premium will also
decrease. But keep in mind that this is
a maximum value. If your car gets stolen
or gets totaled damaged, then the
insurance company will give you only this maximum liability. So, always keep in
mind that you should not reduce it by mistake
and also do not increase it too much.
You should always decide your premium here keeping in mind the IDV value of your actual car.
Apart from this, the second
factor is NCB
discount. What is NCB discount?
If you do not make a claim here in
any year and if you do not make a claim continuously for five
years, then you get an NCB
discount of 50%, that is, it starts getting levied from the second year.
Suppose you did not make any claim in the
first year, then you will get 20%, then if you did not make any claim in the
second year also, then you will get 25%, if
you did
not make any claim for three years, then 35%, then 45% and so on.
If you don't make any claim for 5 years, it becomes 50%. No matter
which company you buy from,
you will always get a discount
here. That is, whenever you
check your
premium here, it will always ask you if
you have ever made an insurance claim before
or how much NCB discount is there in your last policy. So,
according to this table, you
can select your NCB discount. And here, I would
like to give you a big pro tip. Many
times people make this mistake. If
your NCB discount of ₹5000000 is exhausted, then next
year when you renew your
insurance, you will
not get the NCB discount. So, before making a claim,
definitely calculate the cost of your NCB discount. Thirdly, the
main factor in this is your zero depreciation,
which we also call bumper to bumper,
and this is applicable on new cars.
You mostly get this for 5 years,
like when you buy a new car.
You can consider RO DAB for 5 years, but keep in
mind that this is a big factor in
increasing your premium. Whenever
you select RO DAB, your premium
almost doubles here, as you
can see in front of my screen, right now
my premium is only in the range of 4 to 5000,
but as soon as I click on RO DAB,
it will increase here.
Now brother, what does RO DAB mean here,
so see here, whenever
your car breaks down, when you go for repair, all the
parts fitted inside it are
subjected to depreciation.
If I talk about glass parts here, then there is
no depreciation there,
but on the fiber class components, there is a depreciation of
30% and on rubber pipes,
plastic, airbags, tyre tubes, batteries,
all these are subjected to a depreciation of 50%. And
as your car gets older, if
suppose your car is more than 5 years old, then there is a depreciation of
50% on you.  But
depreciation will start to accrue, that is, if
any part is replaced in your vehicle,
suppose the bonnet of your vehicle is
broken and is being replaced, or the
tyre is being replaced, then
you will have to pay the amount of depreciation from your pocket. But the
amazing thing about this zero debit here is that
if
you have a new vehicle, then if
you get a zero debit added to it, then you will not have to pay
any extra money from your pocket for
these parts, otherwise
you will always have to pay the difference in depreciation amount. Apart from this, the
insurance of your vehicle is
given to you by default, from
wherever you get the vehicle released, then there are
many advance covers in it, for some they are necessary, for some
they are unnecessary, there are add-ons here,
so you can save your premium here also, for
example, if I am talking about
return to invoice cover, for this
Suppose your vehicle gets stolen, you get the
invoice value (original invoice
value instead of the IDV value).
Apart from this, it also has 24/7 roadside
assistance. If your
vehicle breaks down on the way, then if you have taken this add-on,
call the company and they will come to
change your tyre or
fill petrol.
Talking about engine protection cover, all the
things related to the engine are
protected here. So,
if you take this add-on, your premium will
definitely increase. So here
you have to see whether this add-on is
necessary for you or not. Apart from this,
guys, there is also a compulsory cover here
which is personal accident cover of ₹1
lakh. So, whenever you
take a third party plan here or a comprehensive
plan, you can see inside it that
whenever you want to check out
with any company, they are going to offer you a
personal accidental cover
which  That is mandatory but here I
would like to tell that many people have some
such debit cards, credit
cards where they have already got it,
well
these things are available in term plans also nowadays, so you have to
check if you have got it, then there is
no need to add it on, this will
obviously
save you premium ranging from ₹500 to ₹6600, apart from this brother, brother,
you have to see how many cashless garages are there in
my nearby location because
what happens is that whenever your car gets damaged and
you have to make a claim etc., then first of all
your car will be given cashless network
facility here only, so you have to check
out which garages or
authorized centers for my car are
with this company, there is a tab here, so guy,
if I talk overall, whichever
company is providing you the highest IDV value
and on which your
premium is coming the lowest here, the one whose claim
settlement ratio is good  There are a lot of cashless garages,
you will find many buy centers near you,
so you
can select such a company here for both own damages and third
party insurance and brother,
I will already give you all these supported links
in the description box from
where you can compare all the things together
etc. Otherwise, if you have any
doubts, please tell us in the comment box.
Thank you guy, thank you very much.